# SIMON WONG

Software Engineer & IT Professional

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

LLUNA - Remote ET (Feb 2023 - Present)

# **Lead Software Engineer**

Full-stack engineer leading the buildout and modernization of an HR Technology startup's core products: the Personal Operating Profile (POP) and TeamOS. Building software that connects people and teams using React, NextJS + Vercel, and Apollo.

IKEA US DIGITAL HUB - Conshohocken, PA (Apr 2021 - Feb 2023)

# Senior Software Engineer

Digital Shopping Experience, Conversion

Full-stack engineer supporting IKEA's global e-commerce products. Drove international customer conversion through innovative technical solutions and data-driven experimentation. Building, deploying, and scaling cloud-based microapplications using React, Node.js, and Google Cloud Platform.

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC - Malvern, PA (Jul 2015 - Apr 2021)

# **Software Engineering Chapter Lead**

Retail Systems - Client Experience & Digital (Apr 2020 - Apr 2021)

Hybrid player-coach contributing as senior software engineer for Vanguard's Client Experience lab. Re-envisioning the investor's digital experience using modern web technologies including Angular, GraphQL, Node.js, and AWS ECS.

# **Technical Project Manager**

Chief Technology Office - Runtime, Resiliency, & Cloud (Sep 2018 - Apr 2020)

Led DevOps platform engineering team in buildout of Pivotal Cloud Foundry runtime environment in AWS. Promoted Site Reliability Engineering practices through improved availability, observability, and learnings from failure.

# **EXTRACURRICULAR**

THE VANGUARD GROUP, INC

Developer Experience Champion | Jan 2020 - Apr 2021 TechTalks Conference Lead | May 2016 - Mar 2020 Technology Leadership Program | Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

CHARLIE'S CRUSADERS PET RESCUE

Website Administrator | May 2018 - Present

PENN STATE IFC/PANHELLENIC DANCE MARATHON **Technology Committee Captain** | Apr 2014 - Mar 2015



#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a professional software engineer based out of the greater Philadelphia area with experience in technical leadership and full stack web development.

My passions include building beautiful software products with a client-centric lens, embracing the DevOps mindset, and crafting an engineering culture that celebrates inclusion and innovation.

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S.E. Software Engineering Penn State University '19

B.S. Information Sciences & Technology

Penn State University '15

# TECHNICAL SKILLS Front-End

- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, Angular, Sass
- Jest, React Testing Library
- Optimizely Web & Full-Stack

#### Back-End

- Node.js, Express.js
- GraphQL, Apollo, urql
- Prisma, PostgreSQL

#### Operations & Infrastructure

- AWS, GCP, Vercel
- Splunk, Sentry, Datadog
- CI/CD Pipelines

### **GET IN TOUCH**

www.simonwong.dev





hello@simonwong.dev